hi i'm chris castle with solid box TV
and today i'm going to show you the m50
510 and 7510 workstations from Dell
first off you may be familiar with the M
3800 and the M 4,800 workstations from
Dell these are essentially the
replacements of those two workstations
they're a significant improvement over
those two laptops so we'll go into an
in-depth review of each of these
products and see which one you like
better alright start with the Dell 5510
some specs on here first off it can
handle the xeon processors as well as
the i7 processors it can handle up to 32
gigabytes of RAM and when you're running
at 32 gigabytes of RAM the speed on that
Ram will be limited to 20 133 megahertz
SDRAM and those are two dims that are
gonna be non-ecc okay so if you have the
Xeon and you have 32 gigabytes of RAM
that's a non-ecc configuration the
graphics card right off the bat is the
Quadro M 1000 M that's a 2 gigabyte card
that runs a monitor external monitor all
the way up to a 4k external monitor the
display that's built into the laptop is
a 15.6 inch ultra sharp F HD IPS and of
course that's a LED backlit and so
that's going to give you 1920 by 1080
resolution what we love about this
screen is that it's anti glare so it's a
very crisp vibrant display yet there's
no glare from the back like you would
have liked with some of these consumer
model laptops and so just as far as
working on this every day this is gonna
be very easy on your eyes but for most
people this is a travel laptop it's a
smaller one that replaces in 1300 so
really you're gonna use this display
quite a bit so that's why you want it to
be a good display in terms of hard drive
will typically do is a single 256
gigabyte PCIe hard drive as a primary
which where we put our OS and our
programs and then we'll have a secondary
data drive another 512 solid-state drive
in there now if you're the kind of
person who just wants one single drive
the PCIe or can handle up to at 512
gigabyte Drive and that's that's
sufficient for most people especially
this is a travel laptop core sports
let's talk about that we got one
Thunderbolt port on here as a
thunderbolt three got two USB 3.0 ports
with the power sheriff so obviously
there's either powered enough to power
those external devices HDMI of course
for your display and then of course
there's a built in camera and webbed
headphone jack in the microphone combo
the Eldon one-eighth inch Jack here that
was very important point out here is if
you're going to use the Dell docking
station that we sell you can use one of
those USB 3.0 ports to power that but we
find the most typical configuration for
people to use external monitor is to use
that HDMI output it's the most
responsive output for your display
there's an SD card reader in that of
course can handle SD cards up to 64
gigabytes dimension wise the laptop is
the thinnest that Dell makes at point 4
or 5 inches the weight and that's what's
remarkable the weight of this maxed out
is about three point nine pounds we're
seeing about four pounds in reality here
Wi-Fi card that's built into this laptop
is the dual band AC card 80 to 60 and
that also has a bluetooth 4.1 card built
into it all integrated so it's a very
robust card you're gonna pick up all
sorts of Wi-Fi networks with this is the
ultimate travel Wi-Fi card you could
have now let's talk about the battery
life on this what's really the reality
here with battery life well this is a
3-cell battery 56 watt hours of battery
life it's lithium ion so the good thing
is is this battery charge is really fast
it has the Express charge technology of
course the power adapter that goes with
that is 130 watt AC adapter fortunately
that's not a huge adapter so it's not
like the old bricks that you used to
have with these workstations so the good
news is it charges quickly battery life
we're seeing pretty much between three
to four hours of using solidworks and
programs that are really intense and if
you're doing stuff like word processing
and stuff you could see up to six hours
now if you're looking for a budget
processor to go with your fifty five ten
you can go down to an i5 processor or i7
in both cases they're great alternatives
to the Xeon what you're getting out of
the xeon obviously is the little bit of
stability in multitasking but let's just
be honest here this is a travel laptop
you could probably be very happy with
the i5 processor that runs at 2.3
gigahertz turbos into three points you
and then the better eye 7 is an i7 6820
HQ it's also a quad core processor same
pretty much 2.7 and goes up to 3.6
gigahertz phenomenal options there
you'll save some money if you go to the
i7 over the Xeon for sure alright let's
talk about the e75 10 this is any
outstanding platform but just to make
sure you know right away this is pretty
much a replacement for like the 4800
series chassis where it's thicker the
primary reason why we sell this to you
is that this is compatible with an e
port plus docking station so you can
dock these like you would the bigger
series laptops we've had in the past
like this 6800 and so on so this is
really kind of meant for the person who
is traveling every once in a while but
wants to be able to dock the laptop the
majority of the time and have that
docking station plug into big monitors
to give you a traditional at the office
type workstation experience now let's
talk about specs on this first off let's
go straight to the processor what are
the options here well with this chassis
you have the xeon option you have AI 5
and i7 but this is the same i7 that we
offer in the 55 10 which is the i7 6820
HQ like i mentioned before that's a quad
core running at 2.7 goes all way up to
3.6 in turbo mode the same kind of ram
up to 32 gigs but this is for a gig
sticks working together 21 33 so if you
want to buy one ace from us you can buy
it as little as 8 gigabytes of ram and
later upgrade it to 32 if you want so
it's very flexible in that sense hard
drive same thing we like to stock it
with a 256 gigabyte PCIe hard drive and
make up the OS and hard drive that we
put our programs on - and then we'll of
course with stuff one more hard drive
into that chassis to give you your data
in that case you secondary bay is a 2.5
inch SATA drive port so you can you can
stick anything up to a 1 terabyte solid
state in there if you want to now I
mention the graphics cards that are
available on the 7510 there are two
Quadra cards that are available for the
7510 there's the Quadro and 1000m just
like in the 5510 and then there's the
upgraded M mm M card and the M mm M card
we would actually push that towards
somebody who's working with large
assemblies who's working with programs
that can actually use the GPU but for
the most part the M 1000 M is more than
sufficient for a lot of the solvers
users out there that are even
considering this this platform but just
to talk about the specs on those two
cards on the M 1000 that has two
gigabytes of onboard memory versus the
four gigabytes that are available on the
M 2,000 M so again a pretty significant
upgrade just in terms of the memory
there but the price it is also a
significant factor here when you upgrade
that they display well this is
interesting so we find the display on
this chassis to be a little bit of
regression to the 5510 it's still a 15.6
F HD display with anti clear however we
find that the display is not quite as
good as the 5510 it's still perfectly
fine for SolidWorks but again remember
the mission of this laptop this is meant
for somebody who travels every once in a
while but is more concerned about
docking this into a docking station at
the office and using monitors external
monitors all right so we notice there's
definitely a little bit of a downgrade
when it comes to the onboard display
ports we have a few more USBs here we
have four USB 3.0 ports an MH DP which
is the mini DisplayPort and also mini
docking station ports so you can
actually use one of the third-party
docking stations out there to plug in
this mini DisplayPort slash docking port
that we have here HDMI of course and the
HD headphone microphone combo there's an
SD card reader again supports up to the
64 gigabyte card now let's talk about
dimensions here finally this is thicker
this is over an inch 1.09 inches so more
than twice the thickness of the 5510 big
difference right away by the way that
ice is measured towards the front and
you go to the back it's one point three
inches so even thicker towards the back
there wait now this is where it's a big
difference again you're not traveling a
lot with this laptop this weighs a
minimum six point one six pounds
remember the 5510 was significantly less
it was actually under four pounds so if
you travel a lot this is not the one you
want to use but again more for the
office same kind of quality wireless
card here the Intel dual band AC 80 to
60 the best Wi-Fi card out there in the
market with a Bluetooth 4.1 standard the
big upgrade in this system here is
definitely the battery it's a six cell
72 watt hour lithium-ion battery so in
theory you could go twice as long as in
the 55 10 now this definitely uses the
same processor and graphics card for the
most part so yes in theory you could
definitely get twice the battery power
out of this thing but the part here is
that it comes with a bigger power
adapter it's a hundred and eighty watt
AC adapter with the seven millimeter
barrel and that is unfortunately kind of
more weight in your bag but that's the
power adapter needed to charge that
bigger battery so to wrap this up what's
our take on these two laptops first off
if you travel quite a bit the 5510 is
the obvious choice if you find yourself
in a combination of travel and working
at a desk quite a bit the 7510 is the
way to go but fundamentally these are
both very similar systems they have
pretty much the same platform processor
options ram capacity is obviously higher
in the 7510 but most Alric users will be
very happy with the 16 gigabytes that
are available in the 55 10 in the very
end it's your preference of do you
prefer to dock your laptop or do you
prefer to have a much thinner laptop
that's a lot easier to put in a small
bag and travel with there are excellent
choice for the person that designs on
the road and designs in the office quite
a bit I'm sure you might have some more
questions so please don't hesitate to
call us at 877
697 nine two six nine thanks again for
watching solid box TV
[Music]